number
one there is a dimension of God as a
father Hallelujah there there is a
dimension of God as a as a father
now there are things you cannot ask God
in the F
Dimension but there are privileges given
to you when you approach him as a father
there are things that father God can
deliver
and when I look at that it begins to
reveal to me many times when we talk of
supplies we deal with God as a
father many scriptures that talk of
supply is about God as a father you have
not because you have asked not and in
that day you shall ask my father who is
also your father meaning that when we
come to supply it's our father let us
look at the Book of Matthew 6
possibly beginning from verse
28 when it comes to supply you must go
to God as a father you must go to God as
a as a father and I remember one Apostle
shared a story and he said he was going
through some crisis and he needed Supply
and he discovered when his children need
something from him they always come
where he is pull a seat and they have a
conversation and they lay their demand
so he said I'm going to approach my
father as my children approach me and he
pulled a seat and said father I'm here
and lay the demand and say amen and his
father
answered it's Revelation to know that
name father has ABA and P his daddy so
why do you worry about clothing consider
the lies of the field how they grow they
neither toil nor spin look at 29 and yet
I said to you that even Solomon in all
his glory was not arrayed like one of
these like one of these now if God so
close the grass of the field which today
is and tomorrow is thrown in the oven
will he not much more close you all you
of little faith so their problem was
Faith therefore do not worry saying what
shall you eat or what shall we drink or
what shall we wear these are the basic
things of humanity luk at 32 he says for
after all these the Gentile seek for
your heavenly father knows that you're
in
need of all these things the Lord is
rebuking the
mentality of people seeking necessity
from him as a responsible father he will
take care of his
sons that's why the Bible says them that
believed he gave them the power to be
become the sons of God as a Son of God
it is the responsibility of the father
to
supply I know a woman of prayer and I
wouldn't encourage you to do this every
end month everyone knew in the estate
she's she's a prayer Warrior and every
end month she will tell the Lord father
I have no rent and because we leave the
two of us since I have no rent I believe
you cannot Mis rent
she said in this house we live the two
of us me and you and everyone knows that
I serve you and me I have no rent so
this man please take responsibility and
the father
responded Hallelujah this Revelation is
enough to tell you it is the will of the
father for you to have
food it is the will of the father for
you to have shelter even and own your
own house it is the will of the father
for you to have good clothing he says
whatever the grass what I put on the
grass because that matters a lot you
know Solomon was the richest king he
could afford the best of fabrics but he
clothed himself of course there are
deeper meanings to this but the Lord is
the one who clothes us first with his
glory so this for me tells me there are
basic things are according to God it is
his
will so sleeping hungry is not God
testing
you your house being locked it is not
God testing you as a responsible father
I have never seen a father who has food
for
dogs but not for the children now that's
an example that makes sense that you
have dogs in the house and the father
has meat for the dogs but not supply for
the children if my God has food for the
birs how much more about
me I'm sharing this with all humility
when I received this Revelation some
bills
disappeared because now I knew it's the
responsibility of my father to take care
of my life Hallelujah so when you
approach him you have to approach him as
a son as a son that means you must
understand the Privileges of
sunship many of us don't know because
the way we were taught to
pray the Kenyan
way many of us don't come to him as a
son we come as strangers We Begin by
saying father we are not worthy to be in
your
presence
disqualification and then we lecture him
and quote scriptures father if we say we
are not Sinners we will be making you to
be a
liar I am not running away from
repentance and we'll come to that but
imagine if your son or daughter came
asking for something and the first
statement is I'm not your daughter or
I'm not your son you'll tell them go and
organize yourself before we have this
meeting because what you are asking for
cannot be given to a
stranger so when we come as Sons there
is the privilege given to us as a son
Redeemed by the blood we are not coming
by our works we are not coming by our
Victory we are coming by the chance of
Calvary we are coming by the Redemptive
power of the Cross and we know if he
gave us Jesus how much more what else
can he give us because the best of
Eternity was Elohim if Jesus was given
to us what else can he withhold from us
you know everyone has something they
treasure and and there is something you
can give me and it's evidence there is
nothing you can withhold according to
Heaven Jesus was the best Hallelujah so
the the first level is approaching him
as a father the second level is when he
takes the position or dimension of a
judge he's still a judge he daddy in the
name father there is abai and p p is the
one that
disciplines every father has good
Dimensions the one that supplies and the
one that also
supplies one is goods and the other one
is
emphy you know my dad used to tell me it
looks like the point is hanging
somewhere let me push it further so he
was not slapping me he was just sensing
I have spoken but the words have not yet
landed so let me help the word to
land and a good father will always have
his words landing and so there is a
dimension of God as a
judge and as a judge we approach him in
two levels one we can come as convicts
guilty in need of
Mercy there are times we know we have
crossed the line we have done that which
were not encouraged to do and there are
times we truly know this is the
chastisements of the Father David has
messed up with BBA and he's going to
fast but the Lord has no patience
because what is affecting David affected
Judah and after Judah was affected the
Lord had to wait for 10 generations for
a man to rise that could receive the
scepter now the man that has risen has
repeated the error of his
great-grandfather now God has no
patience the Bible says it is the Lord
who killed that child so I want to
believe possibly BBA was to be married
by David because out of BBA is where we
get Solomon but David decided to play
God because the first time there was an
an issue of that nature what happened is
that the Lord dealt with the husband of
Abigail so Abigail was widowed and
legally David could marry now for bad
shba it is David who orchestrated for
the widowhood of basiba so he played
God and though the man was in prayer he
could not turn the hand of God because
prayer does not untwist
God when you pray well you will land in
the will of God you might go to pray for
a husband but the demand of God is
Revival so day three you'll begin to cry
for England and discover a husband is
not as important as
Revival Glory
Hallelujah and so we begin to see that
there are times when God appears as a
judge and and that will not happen in
the end times even as we walk as
Believers once in a while he will chasti
in US
and in that level when you approach him
you approach him from the revelation of
Mercy if I fall Lord let me fall on thy
hands the revelation of David and the
secret is that he understood God as a
judge but he understood the pathway of
Mercy Lord if you take everything don't
take away the Holy Ghost take away the
throne because the throne without the
spirit is useless I saw a man Saul who
had the throne without the spirit I
don't want that life let thy Spirit not
depart from me oh Lord If I Ever Fall
Jehovah let me fall in thy hands because
in thy hands there is full of mercy and
compassion that is a man that understood
how to go back and he never complained
he said Lord a broken heart and a
contrary Spirit you who sees the heart
of men you can see my heart you know
that I'm after you my heart is broken my
tears are genuine a broken heart and a
contr spirit you cannot reject you are
the owner of cattles on a thousand hills
but I know this sacrifice cannot move
you and the church must understand the
pathway of Mercy Mercy is not ministered
in the place of
excuse sin is hanging on your door or
Cain but you must overcome it where is
thy brother am I My Brother's Keeper
what Cain did not know God never came as
a father Cain was used to God as a
father but this time there is innocent
blood of Abel demanding for justice so
the Lord showed as a judge he never knew
that Dimension and he responded to him
as a father but he did not know he was
dealing with a judge in the courtroom of
Zion Justice is served when man accepts
that I have
fallen no
excuses
Hallelujah and this was the secret of of
David there is also a system where
whereby we approach God as a judge to
execute Justice on our
behalf Proverbs
16:12 there are times when we are
harassed Proverbs 16:12 and we need him
to come and show up the Bible gives us
an example it is an Abomination for
Kings to commit wickedness for a throne
is established by righteousness the
Throne of God is established on Justice
and
righteousness so there are times whereby
we need the Vengeance of God
tithe and Vengeance belong to God those
are the two things that belong to God
tithe and Vengeance vengeance is mind
says the Lord so there are times we
approach his throne knowing that we
cannot engage let the Lord avenge for us
and at that time we are going as the
woman who was seeking an unjust judge
you remember that story Jesus was giving
a parable about the justice of God and
the justice of secular men that woman
was a widow meaning that she did not
have the backup of a man she was
disadvantaged and the church does not
have the backup of any man other than
the one who died for it and so when we
go to God he's not an unjust judge he
says how much more will it be for them
that know him because our matters are
addressed
speedily so there are times where we
must sumon the courtroom of Zion and
approaching him as a judge Hallelujah
there are matters that need the
Vengeance of God in your life there are
people who have attacked you without a
cause there are people who rise against
you without a ground so may the Lord
that avenges for us may this God Arise
that his enemies may be scattered some
of you your divine intervention is that
you need the battle to come to an end
you have been in the battlefield for
such a long time let the just judge
arise and vindicate your
matters there are times when men cannot
talk because their speech cannot be
trusted but there is a judge he cannot
be
bribed he's not
racist he's not on any man's side he's
always on his side so if I be on his
side then I know my matters will be
settled
Hallelujah number three we can approach
God as a king as a king when we deal
with God as a King he deals with us as
princes that's a very I I know now when
we talk about royalty there's an area
where kingship is
understood and one of the things is that
princes ought to understand the culture
and the protocols of the
palace when you are going to the king
though you are the son of the king there
is a level you must take a posture of a
prince
one of the books that teaches on royalty
is the Book of Esther she's a wife but
she understands the protocol of the
palace that when the man sits on the
throne I can't meet him as a wife I
become one of the subjects in the
kingdom and I need the scepter to be
stretched and many times when God deals
with us as a king or we deal with him as
princes you must be ready for
training I saw from the royal family
here majority of the sons have fought in
the Afghanistan
war and they there is no special
Barracks for
them there are times when God will watch
you go through training but he
understands Thrones are not for
volunteers because the patterns of the
old temp the pattern of the old H
pattern of the Old Testament was kings
were Men of War in 2 Samuel 11 it was
the time when kings went to battle that
David stayed at home it's only in our
cultures where kings are ceremonial they
become commanders in Chief but they have
never entered into any
Barracks so they given the sword Bishop
ceremonial and they given the attires
but they don't know the value of
everybody in ancient Israel Kings led
men for
battle that's why David was fighting the
Battle of Saul it was the Battle of Saul
when he showed up golad just said you
know give me a man give me a man from
among your men because the Philistines
have provided a man they are battles
that don't require Barracks they require
man because they are men that God raises
and they don't speak to congregations
they speak to
Thrones
yeah that's why there are fathers who
step in a town and they don't come for a
meeting they come to approach Thrones
you ask Moses
the man was trained to speak to a throne
his Crusades were in the palace that was
the level of Elijah Elijah did not do a
public meeting he shows up and addresses
the throne that is controlling
Israel there is a training needed for
such a man you need to understand Palace
protocols you need to understand the
kingship level of God hallelujah the
Majesty the the the the the approach to
him so many times we go through
trainings but the the king is quiet
because if you ought to be a prince
there are trainings that are
needed and many of us don't qualify in
the training because we are asking why
is the king quiet but the king is saying
this is the culture of princes they have
to be trained for territorial control
they must be the ones to uh take over
the throne and Thrones are guarded by
swords you know know I asked I was
asking the Lord why did the Assyrians
run when they had the amplification of
the feet of the for lepers the Bible
says they had them as if it was a large
army and they had as if it was the sound
of Chariots anytime you see chariots in
the Bible a king must be
involved because the Battle of Chariots
was the Battle of territories the Battle
of arrows was the Battle of protection
so anytime a chariot was launched King
said to be there that's why when Pharaoh
released his chariots to pursue Israel
the Lord looked and realized these men
have no King
K he now had to shift from leading to
fighting because Pharaoh has released
chariots he has moved the battle to the
real of Kings I made Moses a God not a
king because the interaction of of Moses
was you shall be a god unto
Pharaoh but he failed in godhood when he
hit the stone God
speak was told speak to the Rock the man
hit the rock he was told now you have
moved from real of gods to Mortals and
you shall die like a May man he was told
go to the mountains and die there
imagine God telling you to go and
die
Hallelujah God is a our King we must
know when the king is moving we must
understand when the king is moving
Hallelujah who is the king of glory the
lord Mighty in
battle he's the king of glory all ye
Asian Gates be lifted up Let the heads
be lifted let the gates be lifted that
the king of glory may enter that is a
prince preparing the entry of the
king abs stayed by the gates and no one
asked
him but what he did was now to divert
meaning that princes control
Gates the problem was the heart of the
man because they control access to
kingship revivals are when princes rise
and man the gates because the king of
glory will only enter where Gates have
been opened the work of opening Gates is
not the work of the king it is the work
of The Princess and then every gate has
a
head look at Psalms 24 and verse 8 oh ye
heads oh ye
heads oh ye heads Psalms 24 and verse
8 who is the king of glory the lord
strong and mighty Battle of the Lord
begin from verse seven
thank you lift up your heads oh you I
didn't understand what that scripture
meant but I discovered every gate has a
head that head I thought that head is
those two things that beautify the
gate later I discovered that head is the
gatekeeper the manager of the gate so
you can't hijack Gates until you deal
with the
heads that's why this the language of
intercession so it is it is men that
lift the heads of gates and open the
gates so that he can
enter and heal the
land that's now when people talk about
The Gatekeepers of the city and all that
Hallelujah so may the Lord raise
princes and may you not quit in the
training session The Silence of God does
not mean the absence of
God number four we need to understand
when God takes the posture of
sovereignity and
Majesty when he takes the posture of
sovereignity and Majesty we must take
the posture of
subjects there is a real we cannot
question God when he takes the posture
of sovereignity and
Majesty Bishop you'll never remember
this but I remember when I was young I
came and wrapped in your church and you
told
me you have not begun Ministry told me
Ministry begins when you have a couple
and they cannot get children and they
have never missed any conference they
give and they know all prayers that is
supposed to avert barness but they have
not conceived he told me the day you
find such people you have begun
Ministry and do you know there are
things that happen in church that even
us we have no
answers we also rely on God to
explain I remember I attended the death
of a young child and I I knew this is
not the will of God and I didn't know
what to tell the
family that was a very promising child
died because of negligence of the
doctors so I didn't know what to tell
the family but there are times when God
moves in
sovereignity and that's the time we
always say we cannot ask him any
question we were buing one of our
friends he was a musician and the man of
God came was a little bit elderly and he
shared something and everyone laughed he
said you know what if we want to ask
questions he might call us there to
answer us he say so please don't ask any
questions H H and we were all settled in
our hearts and I want to tell you I know
there are things you go through
life and it makes you doubt his
existence let me tell you when God moves
in his sovereignity sometimes he
contradicts his
personality look at the book of habakuk
chapter number one and verse
5 habakuk 15 he even surprises
habakuk he tells them there's something
I'm about to
do look among the Nations and watch be
utterly astounded for I will work a work
in your days with you will not believe
though it were told you this is the Lord
telling him whatever I'm about to do
habakuk even you you will doubt me
because I'm about to use a more wicked
Nation Babylon to judge Israel it looks
like is a contradiction habakuk is
asking about uh intervention concerning
Law And Justice and the Lord is saying
wait a minute the people I'm about to
use to judge you no one will believe it
is the Lord that is responsible so when
sometimes God rises in sovereignity
sometimes we miss scriptures to support
what has
happened in my land no one is above the
law Kenya and one day I was going to the
airport and I saw the first siren car
pass then the second one and then a
motorcycle came I was just driving
listening to loud music and the guy came
and he you know he he was hooting and
then I I lowered my window and he told
me
in I don't know how you say that in
English but it was an
insult and I was still a
preacher I felt like telling him if you
knew the gift of
God and I
obeyed I took the car outside then I saw
the it was the presidential Moto kid
and I realized I've never seen the
president in traffic though the traffic
laws are part of the government laws and
though he's not above the law there are
laws that don't bind
him you'll see all the lights are red
green but the man is passing because at
that time he's operating on Sovereign
power today the former president cannot
attempt we will be two civilians on the
road of course he will have security
more than me but at least all of us will
be low abiding because that Sovereign
power has been taken out of the man so
when God operates in sovereignity there
are things we can't
explain there are deaths we can't
explain there are situations that we
cannot explain and we always amize and
say he's God in good and in bad and then
we come with a scripture that says the
things that have been revealed are ours
and our children those that have not
been revealed they are not ours so there
is a time when we Face matters and we
just come and say Lord You Are God at
the end of the day I will not question
your sovereignity or your existence I
know you have not changed in the year
King Uzziah died I saw the Lord Seated
on a throne the king is dead in the
natural but Isaiah must see a king that
can never die and he seated Isaiah is
moved a relative has died the Privileges
of the temple are almost coming to an
end of the palace but the Lord is not
moved he must lift his eyes to see him
in his majesty the tail of His Garment
filled the temple so the man still sees
him in his majesty and
sovereignity sometimes in our darkest
hour God will not come in humility he
will come in
sovereignity just to remind us I am God
how can job go through what he's going
and then in the last chapter he tells
him prepare like a
man let's talk where are you when I was
laying the foundations of the earth and
job is a victim of a conversation he
could not contribute the devil is just
moving with angels and then the Lord
looks for an opportunity to floss and
brag I said have you considered my
servant job job is just going on with
life he doesn't understand of heavenly
conversations and dealings and then he
goes through a facee in life and when he
prays the Lord answers and tells him
brace yourself like a man will talk
today and after that conversation job
repents somebody say
sovereignity because many people have
left the faith because a door was open
and they didn't understand him in a
sovereign
way the other the posture is when God
takes the posture of
Lord Lord and we have to take the
posture of
ambassadors when he is Lord he's the
owner of all so at that time we just
deal with
delegations look at Exodus
9:1 when Moses was sent he had to tell
Moses what to tell
Pharaoh Pharaoh had stayed with Israel
to a point he thought he owned
them then the Lord said to Moses go into
pharaoh and tell him thus says the Lord
God of Hebrew let my people go that they
may serve me now listen to Israel he was
there I
am that was an open check who do I tell
Israel you are tell them I am the Hebrew
rendering says I will be what I will
be so they want a deliverer I will be a
deliverer a feeder I'll be a feeder they
want a provider I'll be a provider a a
shield a protector it's an open check
and that I am is still there it's not I
was or I will be it's an open Eternal
Dimension I
am present continuous
tense that's why when we sumarize say
he's the same yesterday that's I am
today and forever more that's I am he
changes not but to Herod it was tell
Herod the Lord because that name Lord
means the owner of everything so this
was a conversation that Herod the one
that owns Israel and Egypt wants
Israel so you are dealing with the owner
you are not dealing just with another
Force so the the posture of Moses was
the posture of an ambassador a man sent
in a territory to represent another
kingdom he's going with delegated power
as an ambassador
he's going as an introducer of another
kingdom in another
kingdom and one of the things I
discovered even in the natural Bishop is
that ambassadors are always given what
they call the presidential diary in the
natural and in the presidential diary
they have speeches and responses so if
there is a maybe a terror attack in UK
the the Ambassador will give a speech
and they will say Kenya has spoken and
what he will say is exactly what the
president would have said so every
Ambassador has the presidential manual
because it is the president that sends
him in a territory to present the
kingdom that the president rules now
every good Ambassador must know the
diary of the father because there are
times you will need to respond to life
and you must speak as the father would
have spoken that's why this is our diary
we must Master this book there are times
we speak one day I told the Lord I want
to be a powerful preacher because I
thought power is lifting your hands and
men are falling under the anointing I
realize even witches can make fall
there's a spirit called kalalina Spirit
which makes people fall and then I told
the Lord I want every Sunday to be
healing man and I thought that's power I
want to see cripples walk they sick
healed and all that and one day he
called me for a meeting he said let me
ask you which one do you want a church
where men don't become sick or a church
where you heal the sick which one do you
want a church where you cast out Devils
every Sunday or a church where men
demons cannot live in them because the
the the former looks powerful but the
latter is more powerful imagine having a
church where people don't go to the
hospital because they are under Divine
Healing having a church where you never
cast out a devil because no devil can
live in them having a church where
witches can never bring them down
because they are so powerful that no
power can bring them down I said Lord I
need the L he said embrace my word
because my word is powerful he told me
son if you want to be a powerful
preacher just carry the powerful word of
a powerful God the power in the word
will make you powerful I said I'm going
to read this book because what makes men
powerful is not where they are coming
from no no it's not money it is not
anything it is the powerful word of the
Lord let this book of the law not depart
from my mouth from thy mouth meditate in
it day and night be sensitive to observe
it so that Joshua you can make your way
prosperous and have good
success you can have short men but full
of the word you can have tall men but
empty let me tell you the way to be a
powerful believer is by the word of God
because he watches over his word to
perform it he's the one that performs it
that's why Jesus comes and said we are
now Christ ambassadors we need to
understand who we are because the Lord
has sent us he has entrusted us the
early church they call them Apostles the
sent ones one sent by a king with the
Mandate of the king with the power of
the king with the with the with the
curriculum of the king to go and Conquer
territory for the King K so the Lord is
seeking for ambassadors who will open
the Diary of Zion and understand what
God would have said concerning the
matter you are going through and that's
how interventions begin to
happen so I said
Lord the word is more powerful and I
like what Bishop said he said uh this
may not be the falling meeting the only
things that are falling are strongholds
amen
because when when there is light
illumination there is
deliverance and he said delivered you
know and Bon say deliver the word and
the word will deliver the people so
these are the five postures of prayer
have you understood something